Guide to the Forman Family Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Forman Family Papers
1808-2005
RG 110
Yale University Divinity School Library
6
(15 boxes)
Letters, writings, notes, and collected material document the life and work of three generations of the Forman family. Charles William Forman was an American Presbyterian missionary in North India from 1847 to 1894. His son, Henry Forman, served as a missionary in North India from the 1880s to 1924. Charles W. Forman, son of Henry and grandson of Charles William, taught at a seminary in India for five years prior to beginning his career as professor of missions at the Yale Divinity School, where he served from 1953 to his retirement in 1987. An addendum includes information about the Frederick Marsh family, into which Douglas Forman, grandson of Charles William Forman, married.
Forman, Charles W., 1821-1894
Forman, Henry, -1946
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Charles W. Forman
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
Charles William Forman was born on March 3, 1821 in Washington, Kentucky. After entering the family business manufacturing hemp, he was converted at a revival meeting when he was twenty years old. He felt burdened for the salvation of slaves on Kentucky plantations and tried to establish a ministry for them, but without success. He attended Centre College in Kentucky and then Princeton Theological Seminary. He was ordained as a Presbyterian minister on July 7, 1847 and on the same day started his journey to India as a missionary under the Presbyterian Foreign Mission Board.
Charles William Forman arrived in India in 1847 and two years later settled in Lahore in north India (now Pakistan). He was the founder of the Rang Mahal School in Lahore, the first Anglo-vernacular school in north India. This school added a college department in 1865, which was later known as Forman Christian College. Forman was very influential in developing the educational system of the Punjab area. He served on nearly every committee on education appointed by the Punjab government during his lifetime. According to the Biographical Dictionary of Christian Missions, Forman was theologically conservative, but "favored adaptation of Christianity to Indian custom on matters such as polygamy and he wrote appreciatively of the Sikhs and their founder. He was a friend of all, walking the streets to and from school and talking with the people daily for forty years."
Charles William Forman's first wife was Margaret Newton, with whom he had seven children, including Henry. Following the death of Margaret, Charles married Georgina Lockhart, with whom he had three children, two surviving. Charles' children Henry, John, Charles, Mary, and Emily all became Presbyterian missionaries to India. Charles died on August 27, 1894 in Lahore.
Henry Forman, son of Charles William and Margaret Newton Forman was born in 1860 in Lahore. Following his college education at the College of Wooster in Ohio, he returned to India as a Presbyterian missionary, serving stations in north India from the 1880s through 1918. He was Principal of the Sardars' School in Gwalior from 1921 to 1924, when he retired and returned to Ohio. Henry's first wife was Alice Eliza Bird. Following her death, he married Constance Newton, with whom he had a son, John Newton Forman. Following her death, he married Sarah Taylor on December 30, 1915, and had three children with her: Charles, Mary, and Robert. Henry Forman died in 1946.
John Newton Forman (1863-1917) was a Presbyterian missionary in India and one of the founders of the Student Volunteer Movement for Foreign Missions.
Mary P. Forman (1866-ca.1952) was the head of a Presbyterian girls' school in Uttar Pradesh. Emily Forman (1867-1931) also headed a girls' school in India.
Charles W. Forman, son of Henry and Sarah (Sallie) Taylor Forman, was born in Gwalior, India in 1916. He received his B.A. and M.A. from Ohio State University, a Ph.D. from the University of Wisconsin, and a B.D. and S.T.M. from Union Theological Seminary in New York. Following his marriage to Helen Janice Mitchell, he went as a Presbyterian missionary to India and taught at North India United Theological College in Saharanpur, Uttar Pradesh from 1945 to 1950.
Charles W. Forman was the successor to Kenneth Scott Latourette as professor of missions at Yale Divinity School, serving on the faculty from 1953 until his retirement in 1987. He was Acting Dean of the Divinity School from 1961 to 1963. He was chairman of the Theological Education Fund of the World Council of Churches from 1965 to 1971, chairman of the Commission on Ecumenical Mission and Relations of the Presbyterian Church from 1965 to 1971, chairman of the Foundation for Theological Education in Southeast Asia from 1970 to 1989. Following his retirement from YDS served as visiting professor at seminaries in Egypt, and in the Pacific.
Charles W. Forman died on November 23, 2014.
The March family represented in the Addendum were relatives of the Formans by marriage. Douglas N. Forman, Sr., son of Charles Forman and grandson of Charles William Forman, married Amy March. Douglas Forman was a medical missionary in India for twenty years and later was executive secretary of the Christian Medical Council for Overseas Work, Division of Foreign Missions of the National Council of Churches.. Frederick William March sailed for Syria as a Presbyterian missionary in October 1873, in company with Henry Harris Jessup, whose papers are held in YDSL Record Group No. 117. March and his wife Jennie served the Syria Mission and were stationed in Syria and Lebanon, including Zahleh [Zahle], Tripoli, and Beirut. March engaged in evangelistic tours and literary/translation work and was principal of the Near East School of Theology from 1921-1927. See his autobiographical writing in Series VIII for more information.
Scope and Contents
This collection provides valuable insight on the life and work of three generations of an American Presbyterian missionary family. These personal papers complement the information found in the archives of the Presbyterian Mission Board found in Film Ms. 11.
Series I, Family Correspondence, is primarily the correspondence of Charles William Forman, dating from 1842 until his death in 1894. Additional early correspondence of to and from Charles Wiliam Forman's parents and siblings provides interesting detail on the family and on life in Kentucky from as early as 1808. The early letters of Charles William Forman are written from Kentucky and Princeton, New Jersey, prior to his going to India in 1847. Letters to his mother and siblings from 1847 to 1884, as well as regular letters to his children from 1878 to 1894, describe his life and work in India. Added in 2011 are several letters of Sarah (Sallie) Taylor Forman, second wife of Henry Forman, written on her voyage to India and from Gwalior.
Series II, General Correspondence, is primarily the non-family correspondence of Charles William Forman, but also includes non-family correspondence of Henry and other family members. The elder Forman's correspondence with Dr. Irving, Dr. Gillespie, and Dr. Lowrie from 1851 to 1886 consists of typed report letters to the Foreign Mission Board detailing the progress of Forman's work in India and issues related to the health and support of his family.
Series III, Research Materials and Notes, includes documentation gathered and notes written by Charles William Forman and Henry Forman about the Presbyterian mission in India and the life of Charles William Forman. The Writings of Henry Forman in Series IV are largely drawn from these materials and include an unpublished biography of Charles William Forman, material related to the mission in Lahore, the Indian Famine Commission, and reconstruction efforts of the North India Mission.
Series V, Personal Items and Memorabilia, includes biographical information related to Charles William and Henry Forman; material related to Charles W., son of Henry and grandson of Charles William, is found in Series VII.
Series VI, Material Related to Forman Christian College, includes booklets and other publications related to the College.
Series VII, Papers of Charles W. Forman (1916-), is divided into six sub-series: Writings, Organizational Activities, Material Related to Communism, Collected Material, Biographical Information, and Slides. The Writings include both published and unpublished articles, papers, drafts, and lectures. The Organizational Activities document Forman's work with the Foundation for Theological Education in Southeast Asia, the Theological Education Fund, COEMAR, and the International Missionary Council. See "Intellectual Trajectories" - the transcript of autobiographical talk given at Henry Koerner Center for Emeritus Faculty at Yale for an overview of Forman's work.
Series VIII is an addendum that includes material related to Charles William Forman, John Newton Forman, Mary P. Forman, and the March family.
Arrangement
I. Family Correspondence
II. General Correspondence
III. Research Materials and Notes
IV. Writings
V. Personal Items and Memorabilia
VI. Material Related to Forman Christian College
VII. Papers of Charles W. Forman (1916- )
VIII. Addendum
Communism and Christianity; Education -- India; Missions -- India; Presbyterian Church -- Missions -- India; Missionaries; Forman, Charles W., 1821-1894; Forman, Charles W., 1821-1894; Forman, Henry, -1946; Forman Christian College (Lahore, Pakistan); Presbyterian Church in the U.S.A. North India Mission; Yale University -- Faculty
- Family Correspondence, 1840-1924; Series I
  - Charles William Forman to mother, 1844 Jul - 1869 Dec (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - CWF to sister Jane, 1856 Aug - 1884 Apr (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - CWF to sister Annie, 1845 Nov - 1869 Dec (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - CWF to brother George, 1842 Apr - 1883 Nov (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - CWF to other brothers, 1853 Jan - 1876 Nov (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - CWF to wife Margaret, 1877 Jun - 1879 Jun (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - CWF to niece Mary, 1871 Apr - 1880 Dec (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Margaret Forman (first wife) to Mrs. Ezekiel Forman and niece, 1861 Sep - 1870 Mar (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - CWF to children, 1873 Mar - 1894 May, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9-19)
  - Georgina Forman (second wife) to children, 1891 Mar - Jun (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous letters of family members, incl. Ezekiel Forman (father of CWF) to Joseph Forman, business letters written to George Forman, letters of Whiteman, Tilly, John, Ezekiel Jr., Mary Ann Forman (siblings of CWF) to their mother and other family members, 1808-1850 (Box 1, Folder 20a)
  - Miscellaneous letters of family members, incl. Ezekiel Jr. and Thomas to brother George; from John Newton, Jr. (brother-in-law of CWF) to brother of Charles re. CWF children; to Henry from sister and cousin, 1840 Apr - 1845 Jul; 1876; 1907-1908 (Box 1, Folder 20b)
  - Sarah (Sallie) Taylor to Mary Wood Taylor re. voyage to India via Hawaii, Japan, China, Hong Kong, Singapore, 1915 Nov-Dec (Box 13, Folder 7-8)
  - Sarah (Sallie) Taylor Forman to Mary Wood Taylor re. her marriage on December 30, 1915, and life in Gwalior, 1916 Jan-Mar (Box 13, Folder 9)
    Scope and Contents
    There is a photo of several unidentified women enclosed with the letter of 12 March.
  - Sarah (Sallie) Taylor Forman to Mary Wood Taylor from Paris on way home from India, 1924 Oct (Box 13, Folder 10)
- General Correspondence, 1837-1947; Series II
  - CWF to Dr. Irving, 1865 Sep - 1880 Dec (Box 2, Folder 21-22)
  - CWF to Dr. Gillespie, 1892 Jul - 1894 Jul (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - CWF to Dr. Lowrie, 1851 Mar - 1891 Aug (Box 2, Folder 24-26)
  - CWF to various; Mohamed Abdullah to CWF, 1858 - 1894 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Henry Forman to/from various; Eugene Weld to Sarah Taylor Forman following death of Henry, evaluating his role in the work of the North India Mission; Sarah Taylor Forman to Aunt Mary Wood, 1917-1947 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - John Newton (brother-in-law of CWF) to Walter Lowrie, secretary of Foreign Mission Board and to Dr. Irving, corresponding secretary, 1844, 1877-1878 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Georgina Forman to Dr. Gilliespie, incl. re. death of CWF; J. C. Ewing to Dr. Gillespie, 1892-1894 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous, incl. E. P. Newton to Lowrie, C. Thiede to Lowrie, 1837-1895, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Letter from Maharani of Gwalior to Sarah (Sallie) Taylor Forman following the death of the Maharani's husband, 1925 Jul (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Research Materials and Notes, Series III
  - Early missionaries to India (1813-1840), incl. John C. Lowrie and John Newton (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Early difficulties and adjustment, incl. re. native workers, climate, missionary personalities (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Health problems and death in 1840s (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Culture and religion, incl. re. the Hurdwar Mela and Allahabad Mela, 1840s (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Political and historical events, 1837-1840s (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Education, 1837-1840s (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Missionary salaries and finances, 1837-1840s (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Statistics of religion in India, 1911-1914 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - General, incl. excerpts from diary of John C. Rankin, re. compound and village system, 1836-1842 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - General, incl. re. A. Rudolph, re. journey to Hurdwar by J. Newton, re. preaching at religious fairs, 1841-1891 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - General, incl. "A Short Account of the House Rang Mahal" by A. J. Wilson; Program from 100th anniversary of founding of Rang Mahal Mission High School, 1949, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Mission to Afghans, 1855-1860s, incl. Loewenthal on Kashmir, Bible in Pushtu (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Mission policy proposals, 1869 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Gwalior mission station, 1916-1921 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Sardars' School, Gwalior, 1921-1922 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - "Mission Policy and the New Era" by Henry Forman, ca. 1920 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous, re. India mission, 1921-1923 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Relation of mission to Indian church, 1920s (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Reminiscences of C. B. Newton - "Life in the Lodiana Mission, now Panjab Mission" (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Research on missionaries, incl. letters of C. B. Newton and John Newton, 1869-1872 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Research on missionaries, incl. reference to Henry, Chatterjee, J. H. Morrison, Rudolph, 1862-1872 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Re. Charles William Forman- for biography, 1849-1851 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Re. CWF, development of Lahore mission, 1851-1857 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Re. CWF, incl. schools in Lahore, the Punjab, Sikhs,1840s (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Re. CWF, misc., 1852-1856 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Re. CWF, incl. preaching in villages, Sepoy Mutiny, 1857 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Re. CWF, incl. work in Lahore jail, railway, education, work with outcastes, 1858-1862 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Re. CWF, incl. story of convert, re. preaching, education, 1852-1862 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Re. CWF, incl. re. baptizing orphans, "Week of Prayer", methods of work (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Re. CWF, incl. re. discussion with leading Maulvi, women's work, compensation grants after mutiny, 1862-1863 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Re. CWF, incl. re. college in Lahore, address by Sir Robert Egerton at distribution of prizes in Lahore mission school, re. "virulence" of Mohammedans, 1865-1888 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Re. CWF, incl. reports of "personal labours", report of Lahore Station, report of K. C. Chatterjee, statistics re. Lodiana Mission, remembrances of CWF by Miss Thiede, 1869-1891 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Re. CWF, incl. re. children in U.S, furloughs, 1851-1886 (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Writings, Series IV
  - Of Henry Forman
    - Biography of CWF, chapters 1 and 2: "Of Pioneer Stock", "Boyhood and Young Manhood" (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Biography of CWF, chapter 3: "On the British Bark Coromandel" (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Biography of CWF, chapter 6: "Ludhiana", "Lahore in 1849 and Before" (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Biography of CWF, chapter 9: "Enlarging of Life and Influence" (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Biography of CWF, chapter 10: "The Mutiny Year, 1857" (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Biography of CWF: "Reconstruction Period, 1858-1861", "The Conference of 1862" (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Biography of CWF: bound volume of miscellaneous notes (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - "Note of evidence for the Indian Famine Commission" (4 page printed document), 1898 Mar (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - "Proposals in the matter of Reconstruction in the North India Mission" (6 page typed document), ca. 1932 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Of others
    - "The Story of a Nur Mahal and Rang Mahal boy: Puran Chand Uppal" (published by the Christian Literature Society for India, 1928) (Box 4, Folder 74)
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1847-1947; Series V
  - Forman family tree; clipping from New Orleans newspaper re. Forman family:"An Historical Family", 1894, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Diary of C. W. Forman on his sea voyage to India, 1847-1848 (199 handwritten pages); autobiographical material by CWF, ca. 1891, 1847-1848, 1891 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Obituaries and tributes: for CWF, John Newton,Sr., John Newton Forman, Henry Forman, 1891, 1894, 1917, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Memorial booklets for CWF; Resolution for CWF Memorial Fund from native community of the Punjab, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Marriage certificate for Henry and Alice Forman, 1889 (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - Bookmark with verse, blank postcard, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Photographs: portrait of CWF; "old tomb on outskirts of Lahore, early home of CWF"; "Synod of the Presbyterian Church meeting at Fatehgarh (1886); Punjab Presbytery (n.d.); North India Mission of Presbyterian Church USA, incl. Henry Forman (ca. 1900); Henry Forman and wife Alice Bird, 1886-1900, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Bound volume: "Report of the Punjab Missionary Conference held at Lahore in December and January, 1862-1863" (Lodiana: American Presbyterian Mission Press, 1863) (Box 5, Folder 82)
- Material Related to Forman Christian College, 1854-1964; Series VI
  - Booklet: "The History of the Forman Christian College; Selections from the Records of the College 1869-1936" (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - Booklet: "Commemoration Exercises of the Founding of Forman Christian College at the Quarter-Centenary Celebration" (1911); Issue of The Forman Christian College Monthly re. CWF (1921), 1911, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Booklet: Forman Christian College Founders' Day: Address by Dr. F.M. Velte, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Forman Christian College Notes, "The Anniversary of the Birth-Day of Dr. Forman", 1913 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Forman Christian College Magazine: Pictorial Number, 1925 Mar, Apr (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - The Folio: F.C.C. Magazine: Jubilee Number, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - The Folio: Centenary Number, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Photocopies of original lease and deed of sale of land for Rang Mahal School, 1854, 1862 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Rang Mahal School added a college department in 1865 that was later known as Forman Christian College
- Papers of Charles W. Forman (1916-), 1947-2011; Series VII
  - Correspondence
    - Circular letters from Charles and Janice Forman while serving under Presbyterian Board of Foreign Missions, including at United Theological Seminary, Saharanpur, U.P., India, 1945-1953 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Circular letter from Janice Forman while in Auckland, New Zealand, 1967 Mar (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Circular letters from Formans while living in CT, 1973-2001 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, including letter from DeVerne Reed Smith re. Modekngei movement in Palau, letters from Raymond Arnold, J. T. Hardyman, 1961, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Circular letter written by Rev. E. Y. Campbell, American Presbyterian Mission, Jullundur City, East Punjab, India re. visit to villages of Jullundur District, 1948 Sep (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Tougaloo College while Forman was chair of YDS Development Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 6a)
  - Published writings
    - Bibliography of published writings (Box 5, Folder 89)
    - Abandon Missions to Moslems? The Christian Century, 4 Feb 1949, pp. 128-130. (Box 5a, Folder 89a)
    - Afraid of Evangelism, First United Presbyterian Church Newsletter., n.d. (Box 5a, Folder 89a)
    - The Berlin Battleground, Christian Century, 24 Dec 1952, pp. 1499-1501. (Box 5a, Folder 89a)
    - The Challenge to Christian Exclusiveness, Religion in Life, 27/3, Summer 1958, pp. 352-361. (Box 5a, Folder 89a)
    - Chiefly Because of Our Faith in God: A Tribute to Kenneth Scott Latourette, 1884-1968, Foundations, 12/3, Jul-Sep 1969, pp. 208-212. (Box 5a, Folder 89a)
    - The Christian Confronts the Communist, Crossroads, 4/4, 1954, pp. 39-49. (Box 5a, Folder 89a)
    - Christian Missions in the Ancient World, Propaganda and Communication in World History, Vol. I, 1979, pp. 330-347. (Box 5a, Folder 89a)
    - Christianity and Communism, Crisis strategy - Paper Number Two. (Box 5a, Folder 89a)
    - Christianity in the Pacific Islands. Encyclopedia of Religion, Mercea Eliode, ed. pp.1-9. (Box 5a, Folder 89a)
    - The Church and Castro's Cuba, Signs and Times of the Yale Divinity School, I/6, 9 Dec 1960, pp. 2-4. (Box 5a, Folder 89a)
    - The Church in Areas of Social Revolution, Yale Divinity News, 59/1, Nov 1961, pp. 3-8. (Box 5a, Folder 89a)
    - The Church Under the Cross, The Christian Century, 13 Aug 1952, pp. 923-924. (Box 5a, Folder 89a)
    - Crisis in Egypt, Reflection, Jan 1984, pp. 6-9. (Box 5a, Folder 89a)
    - The Difficulty of Understanding Church Growth in Madagascar, Exploring Church Growth, 1983, pp. 3-11. (Box 5a, Folder 89b)
    - An Ecumenist's Reply, Missiology: An International Review, Jan. 1981, pp. 77-79. (Box 5a, Folder 89b)
    - The Essential Service of the Church, Yale Divinity News, 62/2, Jan 1965, pp. 3-5. (Box 5a, Folder 89b)
    - The Evangel in To-day's World, Canadian Council of Churches, 19-20 Feb, 1959, 23 pp. (Box 5a, Folder 89b)
    - Evangelization and Civilization...II. The Americans, International Bulletin, 6/2, pp. 54-56. (Box 5a, Folder 89b)
    - Excerpts from the 1992 Convocation Dinner Address. YDS in the 1960s. Spectrum. A Report to Graduates and Friends of Yale Divinity School, October 1992, pp.34-35. (Box 5a, Folder 89b)
    - A Faith for the Nations (Korean Translation), 1962, 136 pp. (Box 5a, Folder 89b)
    - Finding Our Own Voice: The Reinterpreting of Christianity by Oceanian Theologians, International Bulletin of Missionary Research, July 2005, pp. 115-122 (Box 5a, Folder 89b)
    - Forman Sees Gospel's Revolutionary Challenge, The Presbyterian Outlook, 143/17, 24 Apr 1961. (Box 5a, Folder 89b)
    - The Foundations of World Unity, Criterion, Nov 1956, pp. 11-18. (Box 5a, Folder 89b)
    - Freedom of Conversion: The Issue in India, The International Review of Missions, ILV/178, Apr 1956, pp. 180-193. (Box 5a, Folder 89b)
    - The Growth of the Study of the Expansion of Christianity, Religious Studies Review, Jan 1987, pp. 30-33 (Box 5a, Folder 89c)
    - An Historical Survey of Protestant Evangelism in India(ms.), 18 pp., annotated. Published in The Indian Witness, Oct 1947. (Box 5a, Folder 89c)
    - A History of Foreign Mission Theory in America, American Missions in Bicentennial Perspective, 1977, 135 pp. (Box 5a, Folder 89c)
    - If One Member Suffers...The Presbyterian Outlook, 144/18, 30 Apr 1962. (Box 5a, Folder 89c)
    - The Impact of Colonial Policy on the Churches of Tahiti and New Caledonia, International Review of Mission, 1988, pp. 12-21 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - The Impact of Western Culture on Asia and Africa. Lecture Study Fellowship, 1957, 25 page transcript. (Box 5a, Folder 89c)
    - Is There a Missionary Message? The Ecumenist, Mar-Apr 1973, pp. 41-43. (Box 5a, Folder 89c)